HANSHIN DAISHOTEN
(阪神大赏典)
SATONO DIAMOND WON
(里见光钻 胜利)
FLAWLESS FORM FOR TENNO SHO
(面对春季天皇赏 毫无死角)
A TIRELESS ATTITUDE, PRIX DE L'ARC DE TRIOMPHE IS WITHIN REACH
(不断累积实力 凯旋门赏近在咫尺)
KITASAN BLACK CONQUERED OSAKA HAI
(大阪杯 北部玄驹获得压倒性胜利)
THE YOKOZUNA OF HORSE GIRLS
(所向无敌的横纲力士)
THE INDISPUTABLE VICTOR
(可说是王者风范)
Hng!
嘿咻
The promising Satono Diamond, who has two G1 wins so far,
GI两胜 势如破竹的里见光钻
and the formidable Kitasan Black, who herself has four G1 wins,
以及GI4胜 拥有压倒性战绩的北部玄驹
the top two horse girls
这两位最强赛马娘
will face each other this spring in Tenno Sho.
将在春季天皇赏中再次对决
As a reminder, Kitasan Black lost to Satono Diamond in Arima Kinen.
北部玄驹在有马纪念中 输给了里见光钻
Will Kitasan have her revenge
她有办法扳回一城吗
or will Satono Diamond snag another victory?
还是里见光钻会继续大放异彩呢
Will there be a dark horse?
又或者会有异军突起呢
"BIG DAY FOR TENNO SHO"
(绝对要去看春季天皇赏)
Let's find the answer in Tenno Sho.
春季天皇赏令人万分期待
Kita.
小北
Ah. You're awake?
啊 你醒啦
Where are you going?
你要去哪里吗
Let's travel a bit, Diamond.
我们去旅行吧 光钻
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
EPISODE 9: PASSION AND ENTHUSIASM
(第9话 热气逼人)
Snacks are ready.
零食 OK
Drinks are ready.
饮料 OK
"SEISHUN 18 TICKET" The travel pass is ready.
(青春18万公里车票) 车票 OK
-Everything is ready. Let's go!
出发准备 完成…
So Diamond, where should we go?
那么光钻 我们要去哪里呢
You don't have a place in mind?
你没有决定好吗
I don't. Should we visit the mountain or the beach?
是啊 要去山上吗 还是要去海边
I prefer the mountain.
我比较喜欢山上呢
But I prefer the beach.
我倒是想去看海呢
Let's decide using rock, paper, scissors.
那就用猜拳的吧
Sure.
嗯 好哦
Rock, paper, scissors!
石头 剪子 布…
The beach it is.
那就决定是海边了
We're heading to the beach.
那就往海边出发
Let's go!
出发
We haven't travelled together for a while now.
很久没像这样两人一起出游了呢
I know, right?
是啊
A racecourse!
是竞马场
"HERE"
(这里)
Oh.
是啊
Bye!
我出发了
What are you doing?
你在做什么啊
I'm checking which beach we're going to.
在查要去哪个海边
You're not allowed to do that.
不可以查
But it's more reassuring if I know where I'm going.
可是先确定目的地比较安心吧
We'll be fine.
没问题的…
I'm sure wherever we go, it'll be fun.
只要我们一起去 不管去哪里都会很好玩的
As long as we're travelling together, everything will work out just fine.
只要是跟光钻在一起 要去哪里都不是问题
Kita...
小北…
All right.
我明白了
If we don't know where to go, we'll decide with rock, paper, scissors.
那要是不知道要去哪里的话 就用猜拳决定吧
Sure.
好
Here we are.
抵达
Where should we go next?
再来要去哪里呢
I want to go here.
那我要走这里
"KEIYO LINE"
(叶京线)
And I want to go here.
那我要往这边
"HOKKAIDO"
(北海道)
Huh?
咦
Rock, paper, scissors.
石头 剪子 布…
Let's go.
好 我们走吧
GOI STATION
(五井站)
FEEL FREE TO LEAVE YOUR COMMENTS
(欢迎列车乘客自由填写)
UMATATE
(马立)
OHARA STATION
(大原站)
We have arrived somewhere far away.
到了很远的地方呢
We sure have.
是啊
Where to next?
再来要去哪里呢
"ISUMI LIGHTHOUSE" Here!
(夷隅灯塔) 这里
Eh?
咦
Voila!
抵达
Wow.
好棒…
The entire world is under us.
整个地球尽收眼底
Mhm. It's so beautiful.
是啊 好漂亮哦
It's my first time seeing this.
我好像还是第一次看见这种景色
Me too.
嗯 我也是
Diamond, thank you for coming with me.
光钻 谢谢你今天陪我出来
No, I should thank you instead.
这是我要说的
We haven't travelled together for a while now and I had a lot of fun.
很久没跟小北一起出来玩 真的很开心
Yeah.
嗯
So?
然后呢
You have something to tell me, don't you?
你应该是有话要对我说吧
Yes.
嗯
I...
我啊…
I want to make everyone smile.
想要让大家展露笑容
Many people support me.
有一直为我加油的人
Some care about me.
有一直关注着我的人
Some cheer loudly for me.
有大声支持我的人
Some clap as loudly as they can for me.
有尽全力为我鼓掌的人
Some are disappointed in me.
有些人对我失望
But some still entrust me with their dreams.
即便如此 还是有人将梦想托付给我
Some might misunderstand me.
有不了解我的人
And some are first-time visitors of the racecourse.
甚至是第一次来到竞马场的人
I want them to be fully invested and immersed in the sports.
我也想让他们热血沸腾 全心投入
I want to bring a smile to their faces with my performance.
我想用我的比赛 让所有人展露出笑容
Therefore,
所以…
I will not concede any more.
我不会再轮给任何人了
I will defeat you in Tenno Sho,
我要在春季天皇赏里赢过你
Satono Diamond.
里见光钻
I just want to relay my goal to you personally.
我一直想把这目标 在这个时候亲口传达给你
I see.
这样啊
I, too, cannot concede my goal.
我也有绝对不能退让的目标
I will win Tenno Sho.
我要赢下春季天皇赏
Then, I will race internationally
再走出世界
and win Prix de L'Arc de Triomphe.
为了赢下凯旋门赏
This is my dream.
为了实现我的梦想
So,
所以…
the winner can only be me.
获胜的人 将会是我
Okay.
嗯
Let's race together.
一决胜负吧
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
The spring sky is clear
一望无际的春季天空
"WELCOME TO KYOTO RACECOURSE" as we approach this historic race.
(欢迎来到京都竞马场) 见证着这场战斗
And this major event will leave a mark in history books and in our memories.
这场春季最大赛事 将刻在历史以及我们的记忆之中
In this race where there can only be one winner,
这场只求一胜的比赛
Tenno Sho will begin soon.
春季天皇赏 终于要开始了
The most highly anticipated match
最令人瞩目的
is the one between Satono Diamond and Kitasan Black.
果然还是里见光钻 与北部玄驹的双强对决
Satono Diamond won Arima Kinen last year.
年底的有马纪念 是由里见光钻夺得胜利
That's right.
没错
Although they came fully prepared and everyone can't wait to see the match,
虽说她们都做好万全准备 令人十分期待这场对决
they are far from the only spotlight in this race.
但这可是天皇赏 恐怕不会让她们两人这般称心如意
Indeed.
您所言极是
They are not the only horse girls who took the central stage.
此次的参赛者 可不会让她们两个专美于前
We have the second runner-up of Japan Cup, Cheval Grand.
日本杯 去年春季天皇赏第三名的高尚骏逸
She must have made a lot of progress in the previous year.
她在这一年里 又积累了不少实力
I'm excited to see what she will bring to the table today.
很期待她在这次比赛中的表现
There's also Divinity, who performed well in Satsuki Sho,
皋月赏赛马娘 神力
and Opheryu, who surprised everyone in G1.
以及大奖赛赛马娘 巨星俳优
Can Satono Diamond outrun these opponents?
里见光钻有办法甩开这些劲敌吗
She seems to be more confident after she won Arima Kinen.
赢下有马纪念后 让她显得游刃有余
I think she's the best horse girl here, bar none.
现在的她 肯定是状况最佳的赛马娘
Satono Diamond expressed her wish to join the Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
里见光钻表明将要挑战凯旋门赏
Can she win this race and reach greater heights?
她能赢下这场比赛 继续向前迈进吗
But there's also Kitasan Black, who's hungry for revenge.
以及要向里见光钻报一箭之仇的 北部玄驹
Despite her loss in Arima Kinen,
虽然在有马纪念吃了败仗
her four G1 wins are more than enough to prove her agility.
但GI4胜的实力是无庸置疑的
I hope she wins this time.
很期待她能扳回一城
"MORAL SUPPORT" You can do this, Kita.
(念力) 加油…加油啊 北部
Redeem yourself after Arima Kinen.
报有马纪念的一箭之仇吧
Another close match up in Tenno Sho. It feels like a déjà vu.
春季天皇赏 双强对决 令人想起那场比赛呢
Indeed. It's just like the match between Mejiro McQueen and Tokai Teio.
是啊 那场目白麦奎因 与东海帝皇的对决
The stage is ready.
舞台已经准备完成
The turf is in good condition. The race to decide the strongest horse girl,
草地赛道良好 最强赛马娘决定战
Tenno Sho, is about to begin.
春季天皇赏 终于要开始了
"A CLEAR WINNER MAKES THE MATCH DULL" McQueen is accelerating.
(对于胜利的确信 有时让人备感无趣) 麦奎因不停向前冲
She did it!
麦奎因办到了
The first horse girl to defend her title,
史上第一个天皇赏连霸
"MEJIRO MCQUEEN, CHAMPION"
(冠军 目白麦奎因)
Mejiro McQueen!
目白麦奎因
"A GLIMPSE OF THE SCARLET COMET" Sakura Laurel is here.
(一闪而过的樱色彗星之光) 樱花桂冠来了…
Can she overtake here?
她能超过去吗
She can!
超过去了
Sakura won again.
又是樱花
Sakura bloomed once more.
樱花再度盛开
"SAKURA LAUREL, CHAMPION"
(冠军 樱花桂冠)
Sakura Laurel!
樱花桂冠
"SET SAIL FOR THE PATH OF GLORY" Lady Charm is on the flank.
(航向金黄色的荣耀航道) 外侧是少女魅力
Gold Ship is in the lead.
领先的是黄金船
She passes the finishing line.
黄金船冲过终点
Lady Charm continued chasing till the end,
少女魅力直到最后都紧追不舍
"GOLD SHIP, CHAMPION" but Gold Ship won by a tiny margin.
(冠军 黄金船) 但黄金船以些微之差获胜
G1
(GI)
TENNO SHO
(春季天皇赏)
With their eyes on the prize,
赌上这唯一的胜利
all horse girls are ready in the horse gates.
所有赛马娘都已在闸门就位
It's now or never.
使命召唤到了
Start!
现在起跑
Everyone tries to secure the lead.
现在在争夺领先位置
The one leading is Tudor Garden.
领先的是都铎花园
Off to a great start, Kitasan takes the second place.
漂亮起跑的北部玄驹暂居第二
Great House in on the flank.
在外侧的是雄伟之屋
Moon Hero, Cheval Grand, and Single Lonely
紧接着是在内侧的明月英雄 以及高尚骏逸
are on the inside line.
再来是单身孤寂
The highly anticipated Satono Diamond is behind the middle of the pack.
双强之一的第二人气赛马娘 里见光钻起跑后位于中段位置
Will this be her third G1 win after Arima Kinen?
这会成为她继有马纪念之后 第三个GI冠军吗
Everyone is watching the race with bated breath.
现在正虎视眈眈地盯着比赛的发展
After the fourth bend, they have arrived at the stretch.
现在弯过第四弯道 进入看台前直线
Tudor Garden is miles ahead of her opponents
领先的是大幅拉开差距的都铎花园
while Kitasan Black maintains her position.
北部玄驹暂居第二
The record for the first 1,000-meter lap
现在通过前半1000米处
is 58.3 seconds.
时间为58秒3
She is way ahead of Kitasan,
居然能比北部拉开更多差距
but...
但是…
Mhm. Kitasan is unfazed and maintains a consistent speed.
是啊 北部完全不为她所惑 漂亮地维持现在的位置
That's a defending champion for you.
这就是所谓的卫冕者风范吧
Tudor Garden continues to increase her lead.
都铎花园以超快步调拉开差距
She's now ahead by six to seven lengths.
已经和后方拉开了6至7个马身
Pay her no mind.
不能被她影响
I am stronger than I was a year ago.
我已经比去年变强不少了
I can overtake her.
一定追得上
I just have to focus on my tempo.
所以现在要集中在自己的步调上
Tudor Garden heads to the first bend.
都铎花园进入第一弯道
Behind her is Kitasan Black, Great House, Cheval Grand, and Moon Hero.
紧追着她的是北部玄驹 雄伟之屋 高尚骏逸 明月英雄
Satono Diamond is in position too.
里见光钻也在这个位置
The race hasn't ended yet.
这里还不是决胜之地
Before the third bend, the Kyoto slope,
在第三弯道前 京都坡道
everything will change over there.
赛况将在那里有所变化
All horse girls passed the second bend and arrived at another stretch.
所有选手弯过第二弯道 进入非终点直线
Kitasan Black is in the second place.
第二名是北部玄驹
Behind her is Great House and Cheval Grand.
紧追其后的是雄伟之屋 接着是高尚骏逸
When will they accelerate?
她们会在哪里出手呢
Satono Diamond is waiting for an opportunity in the middle too.
里见光钻也在中段等待时机
Tudor Garden is still in the lead.
都铎花园依然不断领先在前
Can she maintain it till the very end?
她能撑到最后吗
Now!
就是现在
Tudor Garden seems to have slowed down on the slope.
都铎花园在上坡时慢了下来
Satono Diamond seized this opportunity and closed the gap.
里见光钻没放过这个机会 加速追了上去
The lead Tudor Garden has is disappearing.
都铎花园与后方的差距逐渐缩小
Kitasan Black now takes the lead.
现在北部玄驹领先了
Satono Diamond also closes in.
而里见光钻 也将她追到射程范围里
Patient. Be patient.
忍耐 我要忍耐
The thunderous cheer from the fans welcomes these 17 horse girls.
京都竞马场观众的热烈欢呼 迎接着这17名选手
I will speed up in the final stretch,
要在直线决一胜负
like what I did in Arima Kinen.
就像有马纪念时那样
Here we are at the final stretch.
好的 进入最终直线
Kitasan Black maintains her lead.
领先的是北部玄驹
Ahead by two lengths, she makes a beeline to the finishing line.
领先两个马身奔向连霸之路
Let's do this!
决一胜负吧
I must win.
我一定要赢
Everyone began sprinting in the final stretch.
进入最终直线 所有人开始最后冲刺
Kitasan Black still has her lead,
北部玄驹领先
but Satono Diamond is quickly approaching.
但是里见光钻从后方急起直追
Cheval Grand closes in too.
高尚骏逸也逐渐缩小与前方的差距
Go, Kita!
冲啊 北部
Keep it up!
就这样冲过去
I will defeat you here.
我要在这里赢过你
I will catch up
追上你
and overtake you.
并超越你
What?
居…居然
Another burst after running for 3,000 meters?
已经奔跑了3000米 居然还能再度展开冲刺
Go!
冲啊
Her bottomless endurance, her unyielding spirit,
她那千锤百炼的肉体 和那全神贯注的精神
and the work she has put in so far...
以及积累至今的努力
All that gives her strength to accelerate.
让她强韧地踩下大地 甩开后方对手
Kitasan Black is in the lead.
领先的是北部玄驹
She heads to the finish line with her fiery aura.
北部玄驹以凌厉之姿 冲向众人欢呼的终点线
But Satono Diamond is so close behind her.
里见光钻就在后方不远处
I don't want to lose.
我不想输
I must catch up.
我一定要追上去
It's not over yet.
还没完呢
Come on, Diamond.
我们走吧 光钻
Kita...
小北…
No one... No one can catch up to her at all.
没有人…没有人能追上她
She's alone in her journey. No one can match her speed.
她独自一人领先在前 没有任何人能与之比肩
What an overwhelming lead from Kitasan Black!
北部玄驹展现了压倒性的实力
She far surpasses all 16 horse girls.
领先于16位赛马娘的王者之姿
Kitasan Black crosses the finish line!
北部玄驹 冲过终点
Kitasan Black defended her title!
北部玄驹 达成春季天皇赏连霸
She outdid herself and put up a spectacular performance.
北部玄驹继前回赛事后 展现了超越过去的精彩表现
The trophy cup will once again be held in her hands.
春季的奖杯再度回到王者手中
Taking the second spot is Cheval Grand, who performed a masterclass sprint.
第二名是在最后展现出色冲刺 的高尚骏逸
Unfortunately, Satono Diamond took the third spot.
里见光钻惜败第三名
In this legendary match,
这场众所瞩目的双强对决
Kitasan Black redeemed herself beautifully after her loss in Arima Kinen.
北部玄驹漂亮地 报了在有马纪念的一箭之仇
-Well done. -Yes! That's my student for you.
-好耶 -好啊 真不愧是我的弟子
-Yay!
-太好了
They both did so well.
这两个人都展现得很棒呢
I know, right?
是啊
There's more.
而且…
She completed the race in 3 minutes and 12.5 seconds.
完赛时间为3分12秒5
She broke the record!
刷新了大会纪录
No one had been able to break the record in the past decade.
那个10年来 没人能打破的终极纪录
But not today!
终于被人超越了
Kitasan Black, surrounded by the cheers from her sea of fans,
第一人气赛马娘 北部玄驹 在众多粉丝的拥护下
won her fifth G1!
赢下GI第5胜
Her record-breaking performance
还打破了赛事纪绿
-Woohoo! -will surely leave a legacy behind.
-太好了 -将以名赛马娘的身份名留青史
will surely leave a legacy behind.
将以名赛马娘的身份名留青史
Good grief, that girl...
太猛了吧…
What a thrilling match.
好精彩的比赛哦
You are ranked better than you were last year.
名次比去年更好
You truly have grown a lot.
你确实成长了不少
I am so proud of you.
我对你的表现感到骄傲
Everyone is smiling.
大家都露出了笑容
They are so happy.
大家都很高兴
You took the lead after the third bend.
出了第三弯道后就一路领先
Then, you accelerated on the stretch and performed another burst of speed.
出弯加速 直道线位 最后冲刺
You were impeccable.
你都做得很完美
I lost completely, Kita.
我彻底输了 小北
Congratulations on your win.
恭喜你获得优胜
Diamond...
光钻…
Thank you.
谢谢你
You're always ahead of me and you show me what I have never seen before.
你每次都走在我的前方 带我去看我不曾见过的景色
But...
但是…
We're even now.
这样就一胜一负了
But next time, I won't lose.
下次我不会输的
I will be stronger than I am now.
我会变得远比现在更强
If we run together,
如果是跟光钻一起的话…
we can reach a bigger stage.
一定还能去到更大的舞台上
Diamond.
光钻
Let's bring joy to everyone with our performance.
用我们的比赛 让大家热血沸腾吧
Let's make everyone call out our name loudly
用我们之后的表现
with our performance.
让全世界的人们为我们疯狂吧
Just like what we do in a festival.
就像祭典一样
As long as you're with me,
只要跟光钻在一起
we are invincible.
我们就会无所不能
Kitasan...
北部…
Yes, together,
是啊 我们一起的话
we can do anything.
一定可以的
-You're awesome! -Kita...
-很帅哦 -北部…
-We can.
-一定可以的
Kitasan...
北部…